The first was for himself. The second was for his
country. This time is for his friend.
Rambo III is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Peter MacDonald.
Combat has taken its toll on Rambo, but he's finally
begun to find inner peace in a monastery.
When Rambo's friend and mentor Col.
Trautman asks for his help on a top secret mission to Afghanistan, Rambo
declines but must reconsider when Trautman is captured.
John Rambo, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Trautman, played by Richard Crenna.
Coronel Zaysen, played by Marc de Jonge.
Griggs, played by Kurtwood Smith.
Masoud, played by Spiros Focás.
Mousa, played by Sasson Gabai.
Rambo III is a 1988 American action film starring Sylvester
Stallone as Vietnam War veteran John Rambo.
Directed by Peter MacDonald, the script was
co-written by Stallone and Sheldon Lettich.
It is a sequel to Rambo: First Blood Part II (1985) and the
third installment in the Rambo film series.
Richard Crenna reprises his role as Colonel Sam Trautman.
The film depicts fictional events during the Soviet–Afghan War.
In the film, Rambo sets out on a dangerous journey to the Democratic Republic of Afghanistan
in order to rescue his former commander and his longtime best friend, Col.
Trautman, from the hands of Alexei Zeysen, an extremely powerful and ruthless Soviet Army colonel who is bent on killing both Trautman
and Rambo, while helping a local band of Afghan rebels fight against Soviet forces threatening to destroy their village.
Rambo III was released worldwide on May 25, 1988.
At the time of its release, Rambo III was the most expensive film ever
made with a production budget between $58 and $63 million.
The film was not well received by critics and grossed less than its
predecessor, Rambo: First Blood Part II, grossing $189 million worldwide.
It was nominated for five categories at the 9th Golden
Raspberry Awards, winning Worst Actor.
A sequel, Rambo, was released in 2008 with Stallone
reprising his role and also directing the film.
The film explores themes of submachine gun, competition,
machinegun, liberation, soviet union.
The tone is intense.